<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="route_locations">
        <item>Košutnjak, Srbija</item>
        <item>Avala, Srbija</item>
        <item>Bukulja, Srbija</item>
        <item>Zasavica, Srbija</item>
        <item>Slankamen, Srbija</item>
        <item>Strazilovo, Srbija</item>
        <item>Gradac, Srbija</item>
        <item>Trem, Srbija</item>
        <item>Midžor, Srbija</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="route_images">
        <item>@drawable/route_1_kosutnjak</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_2_avala</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_3_bukulja</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_4_zasavica</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_5_slankamen</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_6_strazilovo</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_7_gradac</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_8_trem</item>
        <item>@drawable/route_9_midzor</item>
    </array>

    <array name="route_lengths">
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6.5</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>14.5</item>
        <item>23</item>
    </array>

    <integer-array name="route_difficulties">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>0</item>
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>0</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>2</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string name="route_label">Route</string>
    <string name="route_length_label">Length:</string>
    <string name="route_difficulty_label">Difficulty:</string>

    <string-array name="route_difficulties_phrases">
        <item>easy</item>
        <item>medium</item>
        <item>hard</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Google translated -->
    <string-array name="route_names">
        <item>A walk through the Belgrade forest Kosutnjak</item>
        <item>Hiking on Avala</item>
        <item>Hiking on the mountain Bukulja</item>
        <item>A walk through the swamps of Zasavica</item>
        <item>Walking from Stari Slankamen to Šapat winery and Novi Slankamen</item>
        <item>From Stražilovo via Branko\'s grave, Grgeteg monastery and the village of Neradin</item>
        <item>A walk through the Gradac canyon, from the monastery of Ćelije to Valjevo</item>
        <item>A walk from Bojana\'s waters to the Trem peak</item>
        <item>On foot to Midzor on Stara Planina</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="route_descriptions">
        <item>
            The trail leads along the wide ridge of Košutnjak, initially through the forest, and
            then over a large clearing, then descends past the ski lift to the tram.

            \n\nFrom the Skojevska bus station (from the direction of the city center), cross to
            the opposite side of the street and take a few steps along the sidewalk. You will
            notice a path among the trees that is gradually moving away from the road. After
            about a hundred meters from the bus station, the trail enters the forest and passes
            by the field where pensioners are bowling. From there, the trail is marked and after
            about 150 meters it leads to the Rubin restaurant. At the end of the parking space
            of the Rubin restaurant, there is a concrete path right next to the building and
            you take it back to the forest. Cross the asphalt road and continue on the wide
            forest road. Cross the second asphalt road and continue along the parallel forest
            path that leads to the left in a large arch, and then to the right, and after about
            500m you will reach the Pioneer City with a children\'s camp.

            \n\nExit the Pioneer City through the gate next to the playground where the trees and
            benches are painted blue and orange. Cross the asphalt road and continue along
            the path to the sign with the large number 9, which leads to the restaurant Devetka,
            which is also located in the forest. Pass by the nine wooden mushrooms behind
            the Devetka restaurant on the forest road and continue until you come out into
            the clearing. Turn left at two red sports fields. After the second red sports field,
            turn left across the clearing onto a well-trodden footpath to a group of oaks and
            a source of drinking water.
        </item>
        <item>
            Crossing Mount Avala from southeast to northwest through the forest.

            \n\nFrom the bus station \"Put za Zuce\", look up, the red and white antenna rises
            exactly on the path that will conquer Avala. Cross the main road to the information
            desk and restaurant Lovac and follow the asphalt road on the left side of the
            restaurant which leads to the forest. Continue left at the crossroads. The trail is
            marked in yellow, red and white, as well as blue and white, and passes by numerous
            barracks all the way to the end of the asphalt road. At that place there is a
            signpost to the top of Avala (50 min).

            \n\nContinue up the forest road and do not pay attention to individual turns to the
            left or right. About 400 meters after the last barracks where there is a small
            concrete wall, the footpath separates to the left while the road through the forest
            continues to the right. Follow the narrow path marked with red and white markers
            until you reach the elbow curve of the asphalt road that leads to the top of Avala
            next to the yellow-black barrier. The marked path turns left and continues slightly
            above the asphalt road to finally turn right and lead uphill along the steep side,
            you reach the red-and-white antenna you saw from the bus station. Next to the antenna,
            go down to the asphalt road bordered by large blocks.

            \n\nAfter about twenty meters, turn left on the asphalt road, and then climb the
            stairs to the Monument to the Unknown Hero and Victims of the First World War,
            which was erected as part of the suffering of an unimaginable number of victims equal
            to a third of the Serbian population, then 4.5 million. From the highest peak of Avala,
            where the Monument to the Unknown Hero rises, the work of sculptor Ivan Meštrović,
            made by the order of King Alexander in the 1930s, offers an incredible view of the
            hilly Šumadija and Kosmaj mountain to the south and Belgrade and the plain of Vojvodina
            to the north. At that place, there used to be a Roman, then a medieval Serbian, and
            later an Ottoman fortress (Žrnovo), a previous monument dedicated to the memory of the
            victims of the First World War.
        </item>
        <item>
            From the park in the center of Arandjelovac, the road climbs between the villas to
            the museum. Above the last houses, the winding Dušan Mitrović pedestrian path begins
            through the beech forest to the tower that serves as a lookout, and then to the top of
            Bukulja, where the antenna is located. There is a possibility to descend the western
            side of the forest to Garaško Lake.

            \n\nCross the road in front of the Izvor Hotel, enter the park and walk a few meters
            to the right end of the flower alley from where the marked hiking trail on Bukulja
            begins. There is a white marble cross at that place. Climb the paved footpath under
            the tall old trees until you come across a few steps to get out of the park. Cross the
            main road and turn left onto the hiking trail that leads uphill. There is an arrow
            on the concrete pillar. Climb the winding road between the houses until you reach the
            National Museum. A few steps to the left of the museum is a church that you can visit;
            and just below, through a beautiful park, is the fairytale (though closed)
            Villa Karadzic. Continue uphill to the right of the museum in the direction of the
            hospital signpost. When you enter the forest and find yourself above the church of
            Bukulja, turn right along the forest road that leads uphill. There is an arrow on
            the concrete pillar on the opposite side. After about 50m of this forest road under
            several houses, the lined hiking trail turns right and downhill, onto a smaller trail.
            There is an arrow on the concrete wall above the footpath that shows where it turns.
        </item>
        <item>
            The route follows the river Zasavica over wide grassy areas and through the forest.

            \n\nExit the circle of the Zasavica visitor center through the gate to the information
            board not far from the observation tower. At that place, there is a starting pillar
            from the row that marks the path. Follow the trail across wide lawns. After some 2.5km
            walk next to the information poster, cross the ladder over the fence and enter the
            forest. Continue along the forest path that stretches between the fields and after
            about 1.5 km you will reach the river Zasavica. The road follows the river all the way
            to the Roma settlement, next to which you reach the asphalt road in the village of
            Zasavica. Continue a few steps along this asphalt road to the path that leads left to
            the bridge over Zasavica. Next to the bridge there is a beautiful picnic area.
        </item>
        <item>
            Blessed with a beautiful view of the Danube and Tisza rivers and two Vojvodina areas -
            Srem and Banat, the route leads uphill from Stari Slankamen to downhills that descend
            past the Roman fortress and countless cottages to spacious vineyards and orchards, and
            returns by a narrow path to Novi Slankamen.

            \n\nFrom the last bus stop in Stari Slankamen, turn left onto the main road and follow
            the green signpost 1 for the Acumincum Fortress (1000m). At the crossroads in front of
            the Catholic church, turn left uphill and follow the Gudur road, which climbs slowly
            around the hill on the left side of the Roman fortress. Behind the last houses of
            Stari Slankamen, the asphalt turns into a field road, and you pass by the cemetery
            that remains on your left. On your right there is a great view over the small islands
            and the Danube to the plantations along the river Tisza and across the open plains of
            Banat. At the place where the field road enters the interior, signpost 8 means the
            fortress Acumincum (350m). About 50m further, at the crossroads next to a small white
            ground floor holiday home, turn left following a handwritten signpost for the fortress
            (100m). Climb the washed-out field road until you come across a one-storey holiday
            home with a terrace overlooking the Old Slankamen. Signpost 9 marks the monument to
            Bici near Slankamen (2500m). Before continuing in the direction of signpost 9, turn
            left and follow the narrow footpath just in front of the holiday home that leads to
            the top of the Roman fortress and the ruins of the tower, also with a beautiful view.
        </item>
        <item>
            From Stražilovo on the northern slope, a winding path leads uphill to Branko\'s
            monument, from where it climbs the asphalt road along the east-western slope. After a
            short descent along the asphalt road, another good forest road descends to the south to
            the Grgeteg monastery. On a low-traffic asphalt road with a counter climb, the route
            leads to the village of Neradin and the restaurant Salash Perkov located on the
            outskirts of the village.

            \n\nBehind the restaurant Branko\'s hut in Stražilovo, a good path along a winding slope
            leads uphill for about twenty minutes to Branko\'s grave (a famous Serbian poet from the
            Romantic era) on a plateau with a view of Novi Sad. Behind the monument, the forest road
            continues. Do not pay attention to the turn to the right towards the mountain lodge
            Stražilovo. A good forest road slowly climbs to the pass at the third kilometer, crosses
            the barrier and erupts on the main asphalt road - Partizanski put. When you reach the
            asphalt road, turn left and descend the marked footpath of about 1.5 km. Cross the
            asphalt road and continue on the marked forest road on the other side (the signs have an
            icon!). The road bends to the right and some 100m goes parallel to the asphalt road
            lower than it before it turns left down. Go over the cottages and after some 500m you
            will come across a covered picnic table with a great view. Go down the pass while the
            Grgeteg monastery remains on your right. Cross the stream next to the monastery gate
            with a golden mosaic.

            \n\nContinue to descend past several houses and farms holding the right side of the
            settlement until you come across a signpost for Neradin. Follow the low-frequency
            asphalt road with a steep ascent to the right, and then descend to the village of
            Neradin, about 4 km away from the Grgeteg monastery, with a wide pass. Descend through
            Neradin, to its lowest part, from where you start climbing again to the next pass. There
            is a signpost for Salash Perkov. When you find yourself on a plateau, turn left and head
            towards the old building of Salas Perkov through its beautiful orchard.
        </item>
        <item>
            After descending the steps to the monastery of Celija and the macadam to the Ecocenter,
            the route crosses the river Gradac for the first time. There are a lot of crossings on
            one side and then on the other side of the river bank. There are fantastic places for
            swimming and grilling before you reach the top of the macadam road, from where the
            walker, after passing through several nicely located cafes, returns to Valjevo.

            \n\nFrom the information board on the river Gradac, not far from the bus station, go
            down the new steps that lead to the monastery, not by asphalt road. Next to the stairs
            there are many picnic benches. To the right of the parking lot of the monastery, and
            next to a large brown sign expressing the welcome to the monastery, a macadam road
            roughly descends. After some 300m walk to the right and upstream, you reach the river
            Gradac. Cross the river over a solid pedestrian bridge made from a trunk to the old mill
            and the Ecocenter. The Ecocenter is a picturesque place to relax with sun loungers by
            the river and a cafe. Instead of continuing down the river Gradac where there is no
            path, cross the meadow in front of the Ecocenter to get to the river again through a
            narrow part of the forest.
        </item>
        <item>
            After the initial macadam path, the footpath climbs through the forest through the
            Devojački grob crossing (1311m). From there, the route follows the slope, and from the
            finish there is a beautiful view in all directions.

            \n\nFrom the mountain lodge Studenac on Bojana\'s waters, follow the macadam road in the
            direction of the blue signpost for Trem, first crossing the ski trail, and then
            continuing through the beech forest. After about two kilometers on this macadam road,
            the hiking route goes uphill along a narrow path through the forest. There is a red
            signpost, nailed to a tree at the turn, on which is written Trem (3h). Follow that
            narrow ascending path, first through a beech forest, and then across a large clearing
            around 1.5am, until you reach a slope at a place called the Maiden\'s Tomb, where the
            Trem is on your left and Sokolov on your right. From the pass, turn left and follow
            the beautiful path, which climbs the divine grass passes for another 1.5 hours, in
            order to reach the top of Trem. The path follows the edge of the Trem massif with high
            cliffs and a spectacular view to your left. The porch can be recognized from many
            locations in Serbia, mostly emerging from the fog.
        </item>
        <item>
            From the hotel Stara planina you can reach a small pass between Babin Zub and Midžor by
            a narrow path below the Babin Zub rock. From the pass, a steep field road leads along a
            wide slope. Behind the first small peak, the field road turns right, and finally, after
            a long but gentle ascent on bare slopes, it reaches the top on the border with Bulgaria.

            \n\nTo get from the hotel Stara planina to the restaurant Plaža by bike, follow the
            narrow asphalt road that turns into a macadam road and passes by the mountain lodge
            Babin Zub. This narrow road turns steeply uphill about 1.5 km from the hotel along the
            main asphalt road in the direction of Knjaževac, and reaches the restaurant after about
            5 km. If you are walking, follow route 27, but due to the long ascent to Midzor, you
            might be able to cross the first part of the ascent by cable car.

            \n\nFrom the Plaža restaurant, descend a few meters on a rough macadam road to the
            lowest point of the pass. From the pass, the macadam road leads to the right downhill,
            following the signpost for Topli Do, which you ignore. Continue straight uphill, in the
            direction of the arrow for Midzor on the big rock. From there, overcome the wide ridge
            along the macadam road, which initially climbs steeply. You may need to push the bike on
            some difficult sections. Pass by the first small peak on your right. From there, the
            field road becomes less steep and begins to turn right. Then go under the three small
            peaks on your left. A red signpost indicates a clear direction for Midzor. The final
            part of the route rises steeper again and reaches the ruins with another red signpost
            and that is where the field road ends. Turn sharply to the left and follow the narrow
            path uphill, and again 100m away we can turn sharply to the right, to reach the top. At
            the highest point of Serbia, there is a white concrete pillar.
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>